# Haye Haye Full-Stack Java Developer

Brooklyn, NY - Email me on Indeed: haye-siddi@gmail.com

Proficient application developer with over 4 years of experience creating complete software solutions and Enterprise applications to client specifications, for internal and external use from businesses to Education and Government institutions. Familiar with Agile SCRUM, as well as a wide variety of technologies and languages. Implemented complex projects through their complete SDLC using advanced frameworks such as Spring, Hibernate, Angular, RESTful web services, SOAP, and design patterns. Adept at back-end, front-end, and interface design, creating readable, reusable code.

Languages: Java, C#, R, PHP

**Web:** HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Typescript, NodeJS, Angular2, jQuery, AJAX, XML, XSLT, JSON, JSP, Servlets, Spring MVC, Spring Web Flow, google Maps

API, Twitter API, WordPress, Joomla, Drupal

Web Services: REST, SOAP, AWS

**Web/App Servers:** Tomcat, Glassfish, Weblogic, JBoss **Frameworks:** Spring, Hibernate, Maven, Junit, Log4j

Databases: PostgreSQL, ArcGIS, MySQL, MongoDB, MS SQL Server, MS Access, Oracle,

PL/SQL

**Design Patterns:** Singleton, Prototype, Factory, Builder

**SDLC:** Agile SCRUM, Waterfall

Tools: PowerDesigner, MS Visual Studio, Eclipse, NetBeans, IntelliJ, Spring Tool Suite STS,

Mockito, Postman, Java FX, WampServer, MapServer, GeoServer, XAMPP

**Subversion Control:** GitHub, SVN **Platforms:** Windows, Unix and Mac OS

Willing to relocate: Anywhere Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Senior Developer**

Ants-Will - Nouakchott, MR - May 2014 to July 2016

Completed on-campus studies and currently taking distance education courses to complete a Master's Degree in Computer Science (Available for full-time, W-2 employment).

ANTS-WILL, Nouakchott, Mauritania • 2014-2016

### Senior Developer

Designed and developed web and standalone desktop applications using Agile development methodologies, including form generation and database management. Migrated application to web, allowing ease of access and maintenance. Proposed successful software marketing plans, increasing client base.

- Achievements: Received Employee of the Year award for restaurant management application development and marketing strategy proposal.
- Technologies: Java, PHP, JavaScript, CSS, NodeJS, Angular, Bootstrap, jQuery, REST, JSON, MySQL, Oracle, PowerDesigner, NetBeans, Eclipse, WampServer, XAMPP, Windows

#### Web Developer

URBAN COMMUNITY OF NOUAKCHOTT, Nouakchott - October 2013 to April 2014

Gathered and aggregated data from GPS positions to develop GIS solution, providing mapping with advanced search options. Created and optimized geographical database, and designed the graphical user interface for ease of use. Developed search modules and map layers.

• Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, NodeJS, Bootstrap, jQuery, REST, JSON, PostgreSQL, ArcGIS, MS SQL, PowerDesigner, NetBeans, Windows, Unix

#### Developer

GTI INTERNATIONAL - Nouakchott, MR - July 2010 to August 2013

Built functions based on provided specifications for company framework, improving development and maintenance of new applications. Designed and developed web applications, including back-end and front- end coding, troubleshooting to ensure accuracy and performance.

• Technologies: Java, C, C#, PHP, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, NodeJS, Bootstrap, jQuery, REST, SOAP, JSON, MySQL, MS Access, PowerDesigner, Eclipse, NetBeans, WampServer, XAMPP

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Computer Science
Maharishi University of Management - Fairfield, IA
August 2016 to April 2019
Master of Science in Information Systems
University of Sciences - Nouakchott, MR
February 2012 to April 2014
Bachelor of Science in Mathematics & Computer Science
University of Sciences - Nouakchott, MR
October 2007 to August 2011

## **SKILLS**

Java (6 years), Javascript (6 years), php (5 years), JQuery (5 years), HTML 5 (6 years), CSS3 (5 years), Ajax (4 years), XML (4 years), JSON (4 years), Spring (3 years), Jsp (3 years), Web Services (3 years), Agile (5 years), Waterfall (5 years), Databases (6 years), Hadoop (2 years), Oracle (5 years), MySQL (6 years), Hadoop (2 years), Hbase (Less than 1 year), Hive (2 years), Pig (2 years), hibernate (3 years)

## **LINKS**

https://github.com/hayeaso/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/haye-haye

## **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

Speak: English, French, Arabic, and Spanish